#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/ghaithhammouri-55b2b514 (LinkedIn) ece.wpi.edu/~hammouri/ (Personal)

### Top Skills

Cryptography Security Machine Learning

### Languages

English Arabic

# **Ghaith Hammouri**

Founder at Mageezo Inc.

Bakersfield, California

## Summary

I am a researcher, an entrepreneur, and a passionate learner. I am dedicated to expanding my knowledge of everything around me, and to bridge the various social and scientific worlds I belong to.

My field of expertise is cryptography and machine learning. I am interested in new theoretical tools that are practical enough to be used in real applications. I have a thorough experience with software and hardware development. I have spent the last decade researching, building and marketing tools that bring innovative technical solutions to people's daily life.

Over the past three years, I have been focused on using Cryptography-inspired tools in order to build a new Machine Leaning/NLP engine to analyze universal languages.

Specialties: Machine Learning, Artificial Intelligence, Information Security, Mobile Security, Hardware Security, Embedded Systems.

### Experience

Mageezo Inc.
Chief Executive Officer
August 2019 - Present (8 months)
CA, USA and Amman, Jordan

#### Simtix

7 years 7 months

Chief Executive Officer / Owner August 2019 - Present (8 months) Amman, Jordan/Dubai, UAE/Riyadh, Saudi

#### **CEO**

September 2012 - Present (7 years 7 months)

Amman, Jordan, Riyadh, Saudi Arabia, and Dubai, UAE

Simtix is a software vendor and a security system integrator. We are one of the most specialized companies within the region when it comes to RFID technology. In fact, Simtix is the first company to introduce Encrypted RFID technology (Gen 2) into the Middle East region.

Over the past 6 years, we have become a proud supplier for some of the largest and most prestigious security agencies around the Middle East.

Crags Inc.

Founder

June 2011 - Present (8 years 10 months)

We provide security consulting for private and public entities. Our goal is to help entities identify and evaluate cutting edge technology in security and cryptography.

Intryca (Claveo)

CTO

January 2010 - September 2012 (2 years 9 months)

Worcester, massachusetts

I oversaw the development of Intryca's core technology security application.

Worcester Polytechnic Institute
Post-doctoral researcher
June 2009 - December 2009 (7 months)

# Education

Worcester Polytechnic Institute
PhD, Computer Engineering (2004 - 2009)

Worcester Polytechnic Institute

Doctor of Philosophy (Ph.D.), Computer Engineering (2003 - 2009)